<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<knowl mode="exercise" xmlns="https://spatext.clontz.org" version="0.2">
    <intro>
        <p><em>Scenario:</em></p>
        <p>A study published in the American Journal of Medicine evaluated the efficacy of a nitric oxide generating lozenge (throat drop) in outpatients with newly diagnosed COVID-19 to mitigate severity. The study was done in 2020 on 524 patients in the United States ages 50-85 who were African American or Latino with a recent COVID -19 diagnosis and at least one of the following risk factors: chronic kidney disease, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, heart disease, diabetes, obesity and smoking. Patients were randomly enrolled into one of two groups: a group that took two nitric oxide generating lozenges a day for 30 days and a group that took two placebo lozenges a day for 30 days. Clinicians who {{blinding}} who was in which of the two groups called the patients at least twice a week to gather a variety of data, including whether the patient had been hospitalized. Patients were also asked to contact the study center or ask a family member to contact the study center for any change in their conditions. The group getting the nitric oxide lozenges {{results}} show a significant reduction in the risk of being hospitalized due to COVID-19 as compared with the placebo group.</p>
    </intro>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Describe the control group.</p></content>
        <outtro><p>The subjects that were given the placebo</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What is the explanatory variable?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>The nitric oxide generating lozenges</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What was the response variable?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>If the patients was hospitalized due to COVID-19</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Did the researchers use any blinding? If so, what was blinded</p></content>
        <outtro><p>{{answer_4}}</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Are the results generalizable to all children with ADHD and emotional dysregulation? Explain your answer.</p></content>
        <outtro><p>No, answers will vary.</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
</knowl>