<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<knowl mode="exercise" xmlns="https://spatext.clontz.org" version="0.2">
    <intro>
        <em>The Scenario:</em>
        <p>In 2019, a group of researchers collected the data from a sample of 222 car models and looked at the impact of different characteristics of the cars on the MSRP (manufacturers’ suggested retail price). They ran a regression analysis. The scatterplots and regression lines are shown below for MSRP vs HP (horsepower) and MSRP vs Engine size (in liters).
</p>
        <p>
        <image source="assets/S6/211P_A.png" description="Scatter plot and regression line showing MSRP vs HP"/></p>
        <p>Below is the information about the regression model for the scatter plot above.</p>
        <list>
            <item><p>Equation and R^2 value for the manufacturers' suggested retail price (MSRP) vs horsepower (HP).</p></item>
            <item><p>MSRP = -3162.10 + 168.64 * HP</p></item>
            <item><p>The R^2 value for this regression model is 0.582</p></item>
        </list>
        <p>
        <image source="assets/S6/211P_B.png" description="Scatter plot and regression line showing MSRP vs Engine size"/></p>
        <p>Below is the information about the regression model for the scatter plot above.</p>
        <list>
            <item><p>Equation and R^2 value for the manufacturers' suggested retail price (MSRP) vs engine size (in liters)</p></item>
            <item><p>MSRP = 18017.87 + 7976.67 * Engine size</p></item>
            <item><p>The R^2 value for this regression model is 0.193</p></item>
        </list>
        <p>Use the two scatter plots and the given information about the regression models to answer the questions below.</p>
    </intro>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Which model, if any, would you use to predict the price of a car? Explain why your choice would be the best model to get an accurate prediction.</p></content>
        <outtro><p>MSRP vs HP is the better model to make predictions with because it has a higher R^2 value</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What do you predict the MSRP of a vehicle with {{HP}} HP to be? Explain why you used the model you did and show all work. Put your final answer into a complete sentence to answer the question.</p></content>
        <outtro><p>$<m>{{answer_2}}</m></p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Would you use one of the regression models to predict the MSRP of a vehicle with an engine size of 3.2 liters? Why or why not?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>No, the model has a weak correlation.</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>There is a dot at ({{point_4x}}, {{point_4y}}) on the MSRP vs horsepower graph. Explain what this dot represents in context of the study</p></content>
        <outtro><p>A specific car in the dataset with {{point_4x}} horsepower and a MSRP of ${{point_4y}} </p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Compute the correlation coefficient, R, for the MSRP vs horsepower model. Explain the meaning of R in the context of the scenario.</p></content>
        <outtro><p>.7629, there is a strong positive relationship between horsepower and MSRP so as the horsepower goes up, on average so does the MSRP.</p></outtro></knowl>
</knowl>
















