<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<knowl mode="exercise" xmlns="https://spatext.clontz.org" version="0.2">
    <intro>
        <em>The Scenario</em>
          <p>Now that the 2022 Midterm elections are complete, the race for the President of the United States to be chosen in 2024 has already begun. Candidates are starting to jockey for position and gather potential donors and voters.</p>
          <p>A democratic governor is considering a run for the White House and wants to know if they will get enough support to make a viable campaign. They do a survey of registered Democratic voters nationwide. They send a survey to likely Democratic voters. They received <m>{{s}}</m> responds back and <m>{{x}}</m> say they would seriously consider this governor if they ran for the white house.</p>
        <p> Compute a <m>{{CL}}</m><m>\%</m> confidence interval for the proportion of {{prose}}. You may use an app to do the computations. You must show all your computations and/or a screenshot of any app used. Please use your work answer the following.</p>
    </intro>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What is p-hat? Please give your answer exact to three decimal places.</p></content>
        <outtro><p><m>\hat{p}={{phat}}</m></p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What is the standard error for this interval? Please give your answer exact to four decimal places.</p></content>
        <outtro><p><m>SE={{SE}}</m></p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>What is the confidence interval? Please give your answer in proper interval format exact to four decimal places.</p></content>
        <outtro><p><m>[{{LB}}, {{UB}}]</m></p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>Put the resulting interval into context to answer the following question: What percentage of registered Democrats are willing to seriously consider this governor if they ran for the White House?</p></content>
        <outtro><p>With {{CL}}<m>\%</m> confidence level, the proportion of registered Democrats that would seriously consider this governor if they ran for the White House is between <m>{{LB_p}}</m><m>\%</m> and <m>{{UB_p}}</m><m>\%</m>.</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
    <knowl>
        <content><p>{{claim1}} {{direction}} <m>{{c}}</m><m>\%</m> {{claim2}} Does the confidence interval support this claim? Why or why not? Justify your answer with information from the confidence interval.</p></content>
        <outtro><p>The confidence interval {{claimtrue}} the claim</p></outtro>
    </knowl>
</knowl>