<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<knowl mode="exercise" xmlns="https://spatext.clontz.org" version="0.2">
    <intro>
        <em>The Scenario:</em>
        <p>Every year several different variables are collected from each state. Three of those variables are SAT scores, proportion of students taking the SAT and population of the state.</p>
        <p>Below are two scatterplots, one showing the relationship between average SAT Verbal scores for the states and proportion of students taking the SAT in that state. The other is showing the relationship between average SAT Verbal scores for the states and state population.</p>
        <p><image source="assets/S6/214_A.png" description="Scatter plot and regression line showing states average 2004 SAT verbal vs the proportion of students in the state taking the SAT"/></p>
        <p>Below is the information about the regression model for the scatter plot above.</p>
        <list>
            <item><p>Equation and R^2 value for average SAT Verbal scores vs proportion of students taking the SAT.</p></item>
            <item><p>SAT Verbal Score = 575.6 - 101.3 * (proportion taking SAT)</p></item>
            <item><p>The R^2 value for this regression is .790</p></item>
        </list>
        <p><image source="assets/S6/214_B.png" description="Scatter plot and regression line showing states average 2004 SAT verbal vs the state's population"/></p>
         <p>Below is the information about the regression model for the scatter plot above.</p>
        <list>
            <item><p>Equation and R^2 value for average SAT Verbal scores vs state population.</p></item>
            <item><p>SAT Verbal Score = 543.7 - .000001446 * (population)</p></item>
            <item><p>The R^2 value for this regression is .077</p></item>
        </list>
        <p>Use the two scatter plots and the given information about the regression models to answer the questions below.</p>
        </intro>
        <knowl>
            <content><p>Which model, if any, would you use to predict the State's average SAT verbal score? Explain why your choice would be the best model to get an accurate prediction.</p></content>
            <outtro><p>SAT verbal score vs proportion of testers is the better model to make predictions with because it has a higher R^2 value</p></outtro>
        </knowl>
        <knowl>
            <content><p>What do you predict the average SAT verbal score to be if the proportion of testers were {{number_2}}? Explain why you used the model you did and show all work. Put your final answer into a complete sentence to answer the question.</p></content>
            <outtro><p><m>{{answer_2}}</m></p></outtro>
        </knowl>
        <knowl>
            <content><p>Would you use the SAT veral score vs Population model to predict the average 2004 SAT verbal score of a state whose population is {{pop_3}}? Why or why not?</p></content>
            <outtro><p>No, low correlation</p></outtro>
        </knowl>
        <knowl>
            <content><p>There is a dot at ({{point_x}}, {{point_y}}) on the SAT verbal score vs the {{ind_var4}} graph. Explain what this dot represents in context of the study.</p></content>
            <outtro><p>The dot represents a specific state that in 2004, {{point_y}} was the average SAT verbal score for the state and {{point_x}} was the {{ind_var4}}.</p></outtro>
        </knowl>
        <knowl>
            <content><p>Compute the correlation coefficient, R, for the SAT Verbal scores vs proportion of students taking the SAT model. Explain the meaning of R in the context of the problem.</p></content>
            <outtro><p><m>-0.89</m>, as the proportion of tester in a state goes up on average the state's average SAT verbal score goes down.</p></outtro></knowl>
</knowl>











