<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<knowl mode="exercise" xmlns="https://spatext.clontz.org" version="0.2">
    <intro>
        <em>The Scenario:</em>
        <p>A researcher is interested in examining the relationships between various characteristics of the human body. She measured 22 subjects to see what measurements were most strongly correlated. In this study, mass is measured in kilograms (kg) and all other measurements are in centimeters (cm).</p>
        <p>Below are two scatterplots. The first shows the correlation between mass and chest size. The second shows the correlation between mass and head size.</p>
        <p><image source="assets/S6/213_A.png" description="Scatter plot and regression line showing body mass vs chest size"/></p>
        <p>Below is the information about the regression model for the scatter plot above.</p>
        <list>
            <item><p>Equation and R^2 value for body mass (kg) vs chest size (cm).</p></item>
            <item><p>Mass = -51.96 + 1.263 * (chest size)</p></item>
            <item><p>The R^2 value for this regression is .602</p></item>
        </list>
        <p><image source="assets/S6/213_B.png" description="Scatter plot and regression line showing body mass vs head size"/></p>
         <p>Below is the information about the regression model for the scatter plot above.</p>
        <list>
            <item><p>Equation and R^2 value for body mass (kg) vs head size (cm).</p></item>
            <item><p>Mass = -51.06 + 2.153 * (head size)</p></item>
            <item><p>The R^2 value for this regression is .061</p></item>
        </list>
        <p>Use the two scatter plots and the given information about the regression models to answer the questions below.</p>
        </intro>
        <knowl>
            <content><p>Which model, if any, would you use to predict the mass of someone? Explain why your choice would be the best model to get an accurate prediction</p></content>
            <outtro><p>body mass vs. chest size is the better model to make predictions with because it has a higher R^2 value</p></outtro>
        </knowl>
        <knowl>
            <content><p>What do you predict the mass of someone with a chest size of {{chest_2}}? Explain why you used the model you did and show all work. Put your final answer into a complete sentence to answer the question.</p></content>
            <outtro><p><m>{{answer_2}}</m> kg</p></outtro>
        </knowl>
        <knowl>
            <content><p>Would you use one of the regression models to predict the mass of someone with a {{size_3}} cm chest? Why or why not?</p></content>
            <outtro><p>No, outside of the data range or extrapolation</p></outtro>
        </knowl>
        <knowl>
            <content><p>There is a dot at ({{point_x}}, {{point_y}}) on the mass vs {{ind_var4}} size graph. Explain what this dot represents in context of the study.</p></content>
            <outtro><p>The dot represents a specific person in the study that has a mass of {{point_y}} kg and {{ind_var4}} size of {{point_x}} cm.</p></outtro>
        </knowl>
        <knowl>
            <content><p>Compute the correlation coefficient, R, for the mass vs. chest model. Explain the meaning of R in the context of the problem.</p></content>
            <outtro><p>.78 and as the chest size goes up, on average so does the mass of a person.</p></outtro></knowl>
</knowl>










